So [music] um we see from the last few
years it's very very much booming the
the world of AI or even the uh [music]
world that's going um around AI because
uh it's very fast it's moving [music]
really fastpaced
>> but we have to balance the risks that
that come with it because not everyone's
trying [music] to design for good.
Well, today I am excited to be joined by
Anitha Mareedu and we are here at
Hollywood, Las Vegas, Nevada for the
Potata First Conference. Uh I you're
smiling big. You you had a big smile
when you walked over here. So I know
that you you're you're with your people
too.
Uh, I've been really excited looking
forward to to coming here and and
meeting people like yourself because
what there's so much buzz around AI the
how we're using it the cyber security
aspects of it. Interestingly enough I've
had a couple of uh opportunities to to
respond to some questions for the um
journalists who are who are asking
because of some recent activities in
cyber like it's given me an even deeper
appreciation. I've always really been uh
appreciative of people who are working
in the cyber space because as a chief
data officer in my previous roles,
if I didn't have people worrying about
that stuff, I don't think I would have
slept it off because it's just a really
really important uh area. So, as we get
started uh in our conversation, I mean
the whole week that we're here is all
about AI. Um, what was it about this
particular event that got you interested
in in in coming out here and and what
are some things that you're a wanting to
to really learn and you know get from
the time here, but al also, you know,
what are some areas that maybe you're
concerned about that you could have an
opportunity to help influence and shape
while we're all here?
>> Yeah. Um, firstly, thank you so much for
having me here. Um, I really appreciate
it and this event is going great and I'm
here uh because of like to learn more
about AI or to learn more about how my
space of or my industry that I'm working
in um can AI like how AI can help or
like to network with the people and to
get to know like to learn more and grasp
things. um as this event is mainly um
data related like AI related data and
stuff like that. So in my area of cyber
security or network security space and
this is even more uh challenging with
all this um AI that's going on around in
the world. So yeah I I'm here to learn
and meet great people like yourself.
>> Wow. I'm I'm the I'm I'm excited about
the the promise that we have here with
with AI. But I think, you know, some of
the things that I've heard about over
the last couple years, I didn't even
know this until someone, you know,
forwarded me an article. Um, but it was
this spring just coming out of the the
the worst part of the pandemic that one
of the biggest cyber attacks in the US
happened during that period of time. And
there's like there's just one example of
of how pervasive um the nefarious
activity can be in in cyber. And I'm not
sure if you're familiar with this
particular incident that I'm referring
to, but um there were literally millions
of uh access points that people were
firing messages at the the NIH and
apparently didn't do anything to take
anything offline, but it clearly was
designed to bombard the thing and look
for vulnerabilities. Um, tell me a
little bit about what got you interested
in cyber security and and what are some
of your observations and as you've
gotten into it and maybe talk a little
bit about that and if it's something
you're familiar with and and how should
we be thinking about it and how do we
advise our friends and colleagues who
are working in the AI space? I mean,
it's exciting, but we have to balance
the risks that that come with it because
not everyone's trying to design for
good.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. Um that's a
great question. So uh to answer your
first question like what interests me to
this uh field is uh so pre initially I
started my work my career in networking
as a network engineer uh because I did
my masters in um by taking some courses
in network field though I'm an
electrical engineering and I did my
thesis in real I did my research in real
and stuff but also I took my courses in
networking and security while doing that
taking some certifications s in the
field. uh that interested me and once I
started working off as a network
engineer and I see that we can create so
much about it like it we can talk from
anywhere in the world using this network
uh creating the routes and like you know
all the way from layer 1 to four and
then um uh about the layer 7 or about
the security stuff is what uh intrigued
me because nowadays as uh time is going
on we see a lot of applications around
the world, right? So, um and then
application security has become a very
much uh prominent um in the recent times
like app security or API uh security
when we talk about it. So, um that
introved me like security the breaches
or the attacks that keep on happening.
So, how we can defend these right? So,
uh that kind of interests me and I
started taking courses. I started
training myself um uh in the
certification through the certifications
it can be or the courses that we have
online. So um and while I am working on
it that really interests me to get into
this field of security and um I have
worked on um a few areas of security
like I have worked on the endpoint side
of security. I have worked on network
security basically on the defense side
um working on different um firewalls
like it can be uh different different
vendors that we have out right there
outside like uh it can be Cisco, Palo
Alto, Checkpoint, Juniper and so on to
name a few. So um I have worked on
different areas of that and I also
worked on um different layers of
security. So it can be uh to prevent the
attacks or breaches through IDPS tools
or um it can be all the way from user
identification, user ID all the way to
the um network security and like you
know endpoint side. So um when I worked
on so basically I have had the
experience to work on a holistic view
right um the whole ecosystem of security
all the way from um layer 1 to all the
way to layer 7 as well as covering from
user ID to all the way to the parimeter
side of the security. So um when we talk
about um AI or even we talk about
agentic AI or AI LLM models and stuff.
So um we see from the last few years
it's very very much booming the the word
of AI or even the uh work that's going
um around AI because uh it's very fast
it's moving really fast-paced and um um
we can also see that um a lot of the uh
work that we can do probably in hours
probably can be done in minutes now uh
by deploying but at the same time we
need to um we need to uh be vigilant
about um where we are deploying them and
how we are deploying them and um is it
really needed and if it is needed how we
can also secure it right because um at
the end of the day uh again security
matters a lot because if we are
deploying some kind of agentic AI or any
kind of AI if we are deploying it and
we're just giving it the power to do it
then we also need to um secure about it.
Uh how we how much access we can give to
what so
yeah
>> yeah you're you're touching on a really
important thing and it's how much data
and what data can we give it and I I
think you know when I've thought about
uh bias for example the thing that's
always been more of a concern to me and
and don't don't misunderstand I know
there's people who are actively trying
to you know breach systems and do things
that are just beyond my imagination why
they would want to u clearly somebody is
either making them very wealthy or they
just have a very very different mindset
than I do. I don't know which maybe is
both. Um but the the pieces that are
concerning
from a national security perspective for
example there's information that you
don't necessarily want everybody to
have. Um, if I think back, um, when the
first Gulf War was about to unfold, uh,
we first heard about stealth technology
at that point in time, it was clo, it
was over 20 years old, closer to 30
years old at that point where the
American public even became aware of it.
Um, it's a good example of something
that you don't necessarily want exposed.
You don't want to put it in just every
model. Um, but as we think about AI,
just from a a general perspective, are
there industries that you think that we
should be concerned about um that have a
tendency to be a lot less um stringent
about securing than than others? And I'm
not talking about that, you know, the
big data aggregate is because we I mean
they know that they've got a bullseye on
them. So, and I would hesitate to even
guess uh the the uh number of hours of
sleep that get lost on a regular basis
by people responsible for those and
their companies. Uh but you what are
some things what are some of the
industries that you think are are of
concern at this point? I I mean I think
about a lot of different things like in
the finance healthcare space and
whatever but from your experience you
know what are your what are you seeing
and and where should we we be looking
and paying attention and learning from
whether they're making good decisions or
making some mistakes.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um so that's a great
question. I have worked with different
industries. I have worked in the
advertising product based companies. I
have worked in the social media company.
I have worked with uh security company
itself and now I'm working with that
chip designing designing company. So um
in my experience that I see um so if we
talk about the CIA trade right and
security which is confidentiality
integrity and availability so um each is
concerned with each different area of
sector right like if you're talking
about a government sector it's um
confidentiality matters a lot and uh
integrity of course it's very much
important when we talk about any kind of
principles in security because the data
have to be intact and uh when we talk
about availability. It's mostly about
like the private organizations or B2B
businesses it can be or B2C it can be
right. So you need the availability of
the data all the time. Uh make sure that
there is no downtime.
So um depending on each company or
depending on each organization or the
sector that you are in it matters like
what type of data that you need to
protect. So um when we are talking about
like let me say like a health
organizations like um principles like
HIPPA comes into picture right. So um we
need to make sure that the data the
privacy is not being compromised like PI
PI data personal identifiable
information is not being uh compromised.
So um the same goes with the finance
sectors like banking sectors where you
have a lot of information which needs to
be very much um like of users data. Uh
there's a lot of users data in uh both
the health sector as well as the finance
sector. So you need to make sure that
what exceptions that you're giving or
what um data or PI data how much
prediction you are uh putting there the
policies uh the best practices that
needs to be followed or the uh
principles that you need to um follow it
can be nest HIPPA or sock getting all of
these in place. So uh that matters a lot
uh depending on the industry that you
are in or depending on the industry that
you are trying to partner with or having
those customers or like you know
integrating with. So um in in that way
we need to also comply with that uh
principles and sector depending on the
sectors that you are with. Yeah, the
adaptability and the the nuance to
different industries I can imagine is is
a big challenge for you as you're, you
know, trying to find the right
solutions. U you you talked about, you
know, educating yourself and I I I'm
glad you said that because I I I really
want to make sure that people are
hearing um the the the things that they
should be really thinking about doing
for themselves because there's a massive
fear factor out there. People are
terrified they're going to lose their
jobs to AI. Um,
and there's young people out there that
they don't know whether to be excited or
scared because they're they get excited,
but their parents are probably trying to
put guard rails around them trying to
get them to be careful and all that. But
what would you tell people they should
be doing if if they they're realizing
that this is here to stay?
What should they do? What can they do?
Um, and especially if you you seem
passionate about what you do, maybe that
uh you can inspire some folks that may
may listen to our podcast. What are some
things that you would tell them from
your own experience? And and what can
they be doing to really take advantage
of the moment that we're in? This is
probably at least 10x as transformative
as the internet coming on the scene in
the '9s. It's massive
>> disrupion. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I totally
agree with you. and people like new
grads who are just graduating or the
people who are trying to the students
who are trying to get into the education
like you know who are coming for masters
to us or it can be uh for bachelors
right or even the people around the
world but we know that United States of
America is the place um to start
anything uh at the foremost right and we
know that Silicon Valley is the place
where everything just starts and we can
see already big tech companies like
Fanga companies or um who already
started from the last uh two years they
have been trying to do a lot of hiring
in the AI uh sector um rather than a
traditional work or even uh in the areas
of where uh you can just replace um
people with um like you know it can be
networking it can be a software
developers or everywhere right so
they're seeing to u have like one person
do 10 things using AI
>> right
>> kind of a technology so Um I would say
to anyone who is interested in pursuing
uh and who are really interested in
learning more about um like you know uh
it can be like you know AI area or it
can be on developing uh something
related to like learning new models or
languages um or even who wants to be in
the area of security or maybe in finance
or any other sector right so I would
first um ask them to question themselves
what their interest lies in and I would
also uh uh tell the students to have um
keep up with what's because the
technology changes every two years or
every year and it used to be like every
5 years or 10 years before now it's
every 2 years or every year the
technology something new comes and you
need to um learn something new all the
time so we need to um I mean there are
several platforms out there right uh for
example even me when I was uh at the
beginning even though I was an
electrical engineer engineering my
master's degree was in but I learned
myself to get into this field of cyber
security so um the same way I would say
whatever intrudes them uh I would highly
recommend to learn themselves because
anything that is coming out there right
now is new to everyone not everyone
knows everything
>> yes not everyone knows everything so um
the more that we learn the more we know
better than the other person
>> right So, um, that's what my
recommendation would. No,
>> I I love that. I think we need to
inspire people to to go into this field
primarily because the risk seems to be
compounding at a rate that's a little
little concerning. Um, but there's so
much enthusiasm and, you know, I'm
particularly excited that you came to
this event because I think we have to
have people like yourself that are
trying to figure out how can we say yes
to this capability, make sure that we're
using it well. Um there's plenty of
folks who are going to be the ones
that'll want us to pump the brakes. So I
understand that. Uh but the the reality
is somebody is going to continue to push
the ball forward or forgive the sports
metaphor, but it it's going to continue
to advance and we can either be part of
making sure it goes in the direction
that we can live with or we can live
with regret because we fell asleep at
the wheel and saw everything go
sideways. and and that that's not a not
a great area to be uh setting up camp I
don't think.
>> Yeah. In this day and age.
>> Well, Anitha, as you wrap up, um if
people wanted to get in touch with you,
especially people wanting to know where
do I start to learn about cyber security
because I she seems excited, she's
having fun. How will they reach you?
>> Um I mean you guys can reach me on
LinkedIn or um or through email. Uh that
is fine. But uh yeah, I'm always
available on LinkedIn.
>> That's fantastic. I I really appreciate
you, you know, coming by and and having
a conversation with me. Um I I don't
know what the final uh
insight package looks like walking away
from this event this week, but it's been
off to a great start, and I cannot wait
to to hear from from all the folks here
and meet people like yourself. This is
the best place to be. I think anywhere
if you're interested in AI and
technology and cyber compliance. You
just if if you're an AI person, this is
little sights of heaven for
>> Oh, yeah. Definitely. Definitely. And
it's my pleasure meeting you and thank
you so much for this opportunity.
>> Anitha, thank you so much for getting on
the sign.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> That's it for this episode of the Signal
Room. If today's conversation sparked
something in you, an idea, a challenge,
or perspective worth amplifying, I'd
love to hear from you. Message me on
LinkedIn or visit sigarroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming
episode. Until next time, stay tuned,
stay curious, and stay human.